<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Xearth</string>
    <string name="wallpaper_name">Xearth Wallpaper</string>
    <string name="wallpapers">Xearth Wallpaper</string>
    <string name="wallpaper_xearth">Xearth</string>
    <string name="xearth_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="description">Xearth displays an image of the earth, 
        as seen from your favorite vantage point in space 
        (this can be your current position), correctly shaded for 
        the current position of the sun. 
        By default, xearth updates the displayed image every five 
        minutes. The time between updates can be changed via the preferencees settings. </string>
    <string name="impressum">
<![CDATA[
    Copyright (c) 2011-2015 Markus Hoffmann
     ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="preferences_about_title">Xearth V.1.1 for Android</string>
    <string name="preferences_credits_market_publisher_title">More Apps from the author of this one</string>
    <string name="preferences_credits_xearth_title">Credits: xearth V.1.1 for UNIX and LINUX</string>
    <string name="preferences_credits_market_app_title">This app on the market</string>
    <string name="preferences_initiate_reset_title">Short Help on how to use the App</string>
    
    <string name="word_copyrmeldung">&#169; 2011&#8211;2015 Markus Hoffmann et al.</string>
    <string name="word_ok">OK</string>
    <string name="word_copyright">Copyright</string>
    <string name="word_version">Version</string>
    <string name="word_help">Help/Instructions</string>
    
    <string name="menu_projectiontype">Select projection type</string>
    <string name="menu_positiontype">Select view position type</string>
    <string name="menu_viewtitle">View and Projection</string>
    <string name="menu_rotationtype">Select rotation type</string>
    <string name="menu_longitude">Specify fixed longitude&#8230;</string>
    <string name="menu_latitude">Specify fixed latitude&#8230;</string>
    <string name="menu_sunpos">Specify sun position&#8230;</string>
    <string name="menu_magnification">Specify magnification factor&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_shiftx">Specify shift x [pxls]&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_shifty">Specify shift y [pxls]&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_extrastitle">Extras</string>
     <string name="menu_impressum">About/Impressum/Contact</string>
     <string name="menu_stars">Show stars</string>
     <string name="menu_stars2">show stars in the background</string>
     <string name="menu_starfreq">Specify star frequency&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_starsize">Specify star size&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_grid">Show grid</string>
     <string name="menu_grid2">show a coordinate grid</string>
     <string name="menu_time">Specify time&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_timewarp">Specify time warp factor&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_timewarp2">accelerate motion&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_interval">Specify time interval [s]</string>
     <string name="menu_interval2">time interval between updates</string>
     <string name="menu_term">Specify day termination [%]</string>
     <string name="menu_dayb">Specify day brightness [%]</string>
     <string name="menu_nightb">Specify night brightness [%]</string>
     <string name="menu_basemap">Select base map&#8230;</string>
     <string name="menu_overlay">Overlay</string>
     <string name="menu_overlay2">use cloud overlay image</string>
      <string name="menu_markers">Show markers</string>
      <string name="menu_markers2">show markers (Cities)</string>
     <string name="menu_labels">Show labels</string>
      <string name="menu_labels2">Show labels (time, position)</string>
      <string name="menu_shade">Shade</string>
      <string name="menu_shade2">Shade</string>
      
     
     
     
    
    <string name="helpdialog">
<![CDATA[
    <h1>Short help</h1> 
    
    Xearth sets the wallpaper (desktop background) to an image of the Earth, as seen from your favorite 
    vantage point in space, correctly shaded for the current position of the Sun. 
    By default, xearth updates the displayed image every five minutes. 
    The time between updates can be changed with the settings.
    
  <h4>proj_type</h4>
    Specify the projection type xearth should use. 
    Supported projection types are mercator, orthographic, and cylindrical; 
    Xearth uses an orthographic projection by default.

<h4>view position type</h4>
    Specify the position from which the Earth should be viewed. 
    Valid view position types are: <i>fixed, relative to the sun, orbit, moon,</i> and <i>random</i>. 
<p/>
    If you use the <i>fixed</i> position type, you should specify two arguments, interpreted as 
    numerical values indicating the latitude and longitude (expressed in decimal degrees) of a viewing 
    position that is fixed with respect to the Earth\'s surface. Positive and negative values of 
    latitude correspond to positions north and south of the equator, respectively. Positive and negative 
    values of longitude correspond to positions east and west of Greenwich, respectively.
<p/>
    If you use the <i>relative to sun</i> position type the two arguments, interpreted as numerical 
    values indicating the offsets in latitude and longitude (expressed in decimal degrees) of a viewing 
    position that is fixed with respect to the position of the Sun. Positive and negative values of latitude 
    and longitude are interpreted as for the fixed keyword.
<p/>
    If you use the <i>orbit</i> position type the two arguments, interpreted as numerical values indicating the 
    period (in hours) and orbital inclination (in decimal degrees) of a simple circular orbit; the viewing 
    position follows this orbit. Astute readers will surely note that these parameters are not sufficient 
    to uniquely specify a single circular orbit. This problem is solved by limiting the space of possible 
    orbits to those positioned over 0 degrees latitude, 0 degrees longitude at time zero (the Un*x epoch)).
<p/>
    If you use the <i>moon</i> position type, 
    the viewing position is the current position of the moon, recalculated at each update.
<p/>
	If you use the <i>random</i> position type, the viewing position is selected at random each time an 
	update occurs.
<p/>    
    The default position specifier is <i>relative to sun, no offset</i> (such that the 
    entire day side of the Earth is always visible).
<h4>Rotation type</h4>
    Specify a rotated viewing position such that the north is not "straight up" in the center of the rendered 
    image. The angle can be specified either as a numeric value or the keyword galactic. 
    When angle is a numeric, it represents the number of degrees by which the image is to be rotated. 
    Positive values of angle rotate the rendered image counterclockwise; negative values rotate the rendered 
    image clockwise. The keyword galactic orients the image so that the galactic north is straight up: 
    the sun is positioned somewhere on the plane passing through the horizontal center of the screen. 
    The default value of angle is 0. 
 <h4>Sun Position</h4>   
    Specify a fixed point on the Earth\'s surface where the Sun is always directly overhead. 
    The sun_pos_spec (Sun position specifier) consists of two components, both numerical values; 
    these components are interpreted as the latitude and longitude (in decimal degrees) of the point 
    where the Sun is directly overhead.
<p/>
The details provided for position specifiers (see above) about the interpretation of positive and negative 
latitude and longitude values and the characters used to delimit specifier components apply to Sun position 
specifiers as well.
<p/>
By default, xearth calculates the actual position of the Sun and updates this position with the progression 
of time. 

<h4>Magnification factor</h4>
Specify the magnification of the displayed image. 
When the orthographic projection is in use, the diameter of the rendered Earth image is <i>factor</i> times the 
shorter of the width and height of the image (see the -size option, below). For the mercator and 
cylindrical projections, the width of the rendered image is <i>factor</i> times the width of the image 
(see the -size option, below). The default magnification factor is 1. 

<h4>Size</h4>
Specify the size of the image to be rendered. The size_spec (size specifier) consists of two components, 
both positive integers; these components are interpreted as the width and height (in pixels) of the image.
<p/>
The details provided for position specifiers (see above) about the characters used to delimit specifier 
components apply to size specifiers as well.
<p/>
These values default to the dimensions of the screen. 


<h4>Shift</h4>

Specify that the center of the rendered Earth image should be shifted by some amount from the center of the 
image. The shift_spec (shift specifier) consists of two components, both integers; these components are 
interpreted as the offsets (in pixels) in the X and Y directions.
<p/>
The details provided for position specifiers (see above) about the characters used to delimit 
specifier components apply to shift specifiers as well.
<p/>
By default, the center of the rendered Earth image is aligned with the center of the screen. 

<h4>Shade</h4>

Enable/disable shading. When shading is enabled, the surface of the Earth is shaded according to the current 
position of the Sun (and the values provided for the <i>day brightness</i>, <i>night brightness</i>, and 
-term options, below). When shading 
is disabled, use flat colors (green and blue) to render land and water. Shading is enabled by default. 

<h4>Labels</h4>
Enable/disable labeling. If labeling is enabled, provide a label 
that indicates the current date and time and current viewing and sun positions. The position of the label 
can be controlled using the -labelpos option (see below). Labeling is disabled by default. 

<h4>Label Position</h4>
Specify where the label should be drawn. If labeling is enabled, 
geom is interpreted as the "position" part an X-style geometry specification (e.g., {+-}<xoffset>{+-}<yoffset>; 
positive and negative values of xoffset denote offsets from the left and right edges of the display, 
respectively; positive and negative values of yoffset denote offsets from the top and bottom edges of the 
display, respectively) indicating how the label should be positioned. The label position defaults to "-5-5" 
(i.e., five pixels inside the lower right-hand corner of the display). 

<h4>Markers</h4>
    Enable/disable markers. If markers are enabled, display small 
    red circles and text labels indicating the location of interesting places on the Earth\'s surface. 
    Markers are enabled by default.

  <h4>Markerfile</h4>
  If the file 
  <p/>
  /sdcard/xearth/markers.txt
  <p/> is there, 
   user-defined marker data (locations and names) will be read from it. 
   Each line in the marker data file consists of three required components: 
   the latitude and longitude (expressed in decimal degrees) followed by the 
   text of the label that should be used. Individual components are delimited by 
   either whitespace, forward slashes (/), or commas. Components that need to 
   include delimiter characters (e.g., a multi-word label) should be enclosed in 
   double quotes. For example, a line in a typical marker data file might look something like:
   <p/>
        42.33 -71.08 "Boston, MA"    # USA
<p/>
    Everything between a <i>#</i> character and the end of a line, inclusive, is a considered to be a 
    comment. Blank lines and lines containing only comments are allowed.

<p/>
    The marker data file is reread every time xearth redraws an image into an X window. In this way, the 
    marker positions and labels can be dynamic (e.g., given appropriate data sources, markers could be used 
    to encode hurricane positions, where earthquakes have happened recently, temperatures at fixed locations, 
    or other forms of "real-time" data).
<p/>
    Xearth includes a built-in set of marker data for 76 major locations around the world. 


<h4>Stars</h4>

Enable/disable stars. If stars are enabled, the black background of "space" is filled with a random pattern 
of "stars" (individual white pixels). The fraction of background pixels that are turned into stars can be 
controlled with the <i>Star Frequency</i> option (see below). Stars are enabled by default. 

<h4>Star Frequency</h4>
    Set the density of the random star pattern (see <i>Stars</i>, above); frequency indicates the fraction of 
    background pixels that should be turned into "stars". The default value of frequency is 0.002.

<h4>Bigstars Percentage</h4>
    Set the percentage of double-width stars (see <i>Stars</i>, above); by default, all stars are a single pixel, 
    but this option can be used to create some stars that are composed of two horizontal pixels. This provides 
    a slightly less uniform look to the "night sky".

<h4>Grid</h4>
    Enable/disable the display of a longitude/latitude grid on the Earth\'s surface. The spacing of major grid 
    lines and dots between major grid lines can be controlled with the -grid1 and -grid2 options (see below). 
    Grid display is disabled by default.

<h4>Grid1</h4>
    Specify the spacing of major grid lines if grid display (see <i>Grid</i>, above) is enabled; major grid 
    lines are drawn with a 90/grid1 degree spacing. The default value for grid1 is 6, corresponding to 
    15 degrees between major grid lines.
<h4>Grid2</h4>
    Specify the spacing of dots along major grid lines if grid display (see -<i>Grid</i>, above) is enabled. 
    Along 
    the equator and lines of longitude, grid dots are drawn with a 90/(grid1 x grid2) degree spacing. The 
    spacing of grid dots along parallels (lines of latitude) other than the equator is adjusted to keep the 
    surface distance between grid dots approximately constant. The default value for grid2 is 15; combined 
    with the default grid1 value of 6, this corresponds to placing grid dots on a one degree spacing.

<h4>Day Brightness</h4>
    Specify the brightness that should be used to shade the day side of the Earth when shading is enabled. 
    Pct should be an integer between 0 and 100, inclusive, where 0 indicates total darkness and 100 indicates 
    total illumination. This value defaults to 100.

<h4>Night Brightness</h4>
    Specify the brightness that should be used to shade the night side of the Earth when shading is enabled. 
    Pct should be an integer between 0 and 100, inclusive, where 0 indicates total darkness and 100 indicates 
    total illumination. This value defaults to 5.

<h4>Term</h4>
    Specify the shading discontinuity at the terminator (day/night line). Pct should be an integer between 
    0 and 100, inclusive. A value of x indicates that the shading should immediately jump x percent of the 
    difference between day and night shading values (see -day and -night, above) when crossing from the night 
    side to the day side of the terminator. Thus a value of 0 indicates no discontinuity (the original xearth 
    behavior), and a value of 100 yields a maximal discontinuity (such that the entire day side of the earth 
    is shaded with the -day shading value). This value defaults to 1.


<h4>Time Interval</h4>
    Wait <i>intervl</i> seconds between updates. This value defaults to 300 seconds 
    (five minutes).
<h4>Timewarp factor</h4>
    Scale the apparent rate at which time progresses by timewarp_factor. The default value of timewarp_factor 
    is 1.0.
<h4>Time</h4>
    Instead of using the current time to determine the "value" of time-dependent positions (e.g., the 
    position the sun), use a particular fixed_time (expressed in seconds since the Un*x epoch).
<h4>Mono</h4>
    Enable/disable monochrome mode. Monochrome mode is enabled by default on 
    systems with one-bit framebuffers  and disabled by default otherwise.
<h4>Number of Colors</h4>
    Specify the number of colors that should be 
    used. (If markers are enabled (see -markers, above), the actual number of colors used may be one larger 
    than num_colors.) The default value of num_colors is 64.
<p/>
    The maximum allowable value for num_colors is 1024. In practice,
     using values of num_colors larger than twice the number of distinct shades of red, green, or blue 
     supported by your hardware is likely to provide little additional benefit, or, in some cases, produce 
     "banding" effects in the image. Thus, on systems that can support 256 distinct shades of red, green, 
     or blue (eight bits per component), the largest practical value of num_colors is around 512. Similarly,
      on systems that support only five or six bits per component (e.g., many systems with 16-bit displays), 
      the largest practical value of num_colors is probably around 64.

<h4>Font</h4>
    Select a font to use for drawing text labels (see -label and -markers, above). 
<h4>Clouds overlay</h4>
	Select clouds overlay. The overlay is done using a bitmap with clouds.  The cloud maps are not calibrated 
	or carefully geolocated. They are only meant to make the earth look pretty! Instead of the internal (static) 
	cloud overlay a file named <i>coulds.jpg</i> or <i>coulds.png</i> will be used if it is present in the 
	/sdcard/xearth/ folder. Useful cloud-maps can be found here: 
	<a href=http://xplanet.sourceforge.net/clouds.php>http://xplanet.sourceforge.net/clouds.php</a>
	(this is also the location, the builtin cloud map was taken from).
<h4>Alternative Bitmap Textures</h4>
	Instead of the built-in and standard default polygon Map (green and blue), you can use 
	Bitmaps to render the earth. You can select from few builtin maps (topographic and night-electric) and any map 
	file (.jpg or .png) found in the 
	/sdcard/xearth/ folder. 
	This feature can also be used to render the moon (use <i>view position moon</i> to simulate moon phases) 
	or any other planet of the solar system. Even a borg sphere is 
	available.
	Useful map textures (e.g. hitorical, moon, jupiter, topographic) can be found here: 
	<a href=http://flatplanet.sourceforge.net/maps/>http://flatplanet.sourceforge.net/maps/</a>
	(this is also the location, the builtin maps were taken from). 

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="aboutdialog">
<![CDATA[
    <h1>About Xearth</h1> 
    Xearth was originally 
  Copyright (C) 1989, 1990, 1993-1995, 1999 Kirk Lauritz Johnson
 <p/>
 Parts of the source code (as marked) are:<br/>
    Copyright (C) 1989, 1990, 1991 by Jim Frost<br/>
    Copyright (C) 1992 by Jamie Zawinski <jwz@lucid.com>
<p/> 
  Permission to use, copy, modify and freely distribute xearth for
  non-commercial and not-for-profit purposes is hereby granted
  without fee, provided that both the above copyright notice and this
  permission notice appear in all copies and in supporting
  documentation.
 <p/>
  The author makes no representations about the suitability of this
  software for any purpose. It is provided "as is" without express or
  implied warranty.
 <p/>
  THE AUTHOR DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS SOFTWARE,
  INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS,
  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT
  OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM
  LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT,
  NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF OR IN
  CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS SOFTWARE.
  <p/>
Thanks to Frank Solensky for the "-pos moon" and "-rot galactic" stuff.
<p/>
The map information used in xearth was derived from the 
"CIA World Data Bank II map database," as taken from some "cbd" files that were 
apparently originally generated by Brian Reid at DEC WRL. The builtin cloud map
is taken from the xplanet project http://xplanet.sourceforge.net/clouds.php.
The two builtin Bitmap-Textures of the earth (night-electric and UGSG) are taken 
from the xplanet project (original source NASA) and from
<a href=http://maps.jpl.nasa.gov/earth.html>JPL\'s maps of the solar system</a> (NASA).
<p/>
Thanks to Chris Metcalf for the -bigstars stuff, a pile of general source code cleaning, 
and spell checking everything carefully.
<p/>
Thanks to Chris Hayward, Chris Metcalf, Sherman Mui, Dan Rich, and Leonard Zubkoff for giving the 
pre-release of version 1.0 a test drive.
<p/>
Thanks to Greg Hewgill for the Bitmap rendering and overlay extension to xearth. 
He also created <a href=http://xearth.org/live>http://xearth.org/live</a> .
<p/>
Finally, thanks to everybody that sent encouragement, suggestions, and patches. 
Apologies to the many people whose good ideas didn\'t make it into this release.
]]></string>

</resources>